Sassan Joash Moosavinia

Email: simoosavinia@outlook.com Website: sjmoosavinia.github.io/

SUMMARY

ISTQB qualified software tester with 3 years' experience working within Agile development teams. Scientific background with demonstrable manual testing, project management, and communication skills. Passionate about a quality first approach and looking for a new role in which to further develop automation testing skills.

EXPERIENCE

2022 – 23 Software Tester, Bluefruit Software

- Delivered embedded software projects using Agile methodologies and a quality first approach.
- Conducted comprehensive functional, regression, and exploratory testing in all stages of the SDLC, reporting progress and outcomes technical test documentation for clients.
- Represented testing team in client meetings, requiring effective technical communication to gather software requirements and present results.
- Collaborated with testers, project managers, and developers, successfully delivering two projects over a 9-month period, generating £350k revenue.

2021 – 22 Test and Automation Analyst, Cornish Mutual Assurance

- Designed, implemented and continuously improved the entire test process as sole tester in development team for in-house and customer-facing web applications.
- Ran sprint kick off meetings with business owners to understand and analyse requirements, as well as post sprint meeting to demonstrate new functionality and coordinate UAT.
- Delivered payment application with no major bugs, significantly improved payment processing time.

2014 – 21 Accounts Assistant, APCOps Ltd

Managed cashbook and invoices in part-time role within family-run business.

2018 – 19 Senior Instructor, Go Ride A Wave Australia

Led a team of instructors for Australia's largest surf school, teaching classes of up to 50 students.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- Software testing (all levels of testing, bug management and reporting, test documentation)
- Programming for test automation (Cypress, Behave, Selenium Python, JavaScript)
- Agile development practices and management tools (Confluence, JIRA, Kanban)
- Collaborative working and version control (Git/GitHub)

EDUCATION

2022 ISTQB Certified Foundation Level Tester, British Computing Society

2014 - 17 Imperial College London, BSc Geology (2.1)

2012 - 14 Truro School

• A-Levels: Maths (A), Chemistry (A), Geology (A), Biology (B), Extended Project Qualification (A)

VOLUNTEERING AND PART-TIME ROLES

Current Website Manager, The Elgol Fund for Nature (2023 – Present)

- Consulting on digital strategy for gathering and managing conservation grant applications.
- Designing and maintaining company website hosted on WordPress utilising HTML, CSS and JavaScript for added functionality.

Current Volunteer Surf Mentor, The Wave Project (2016 – Present)

• Mentoring disadvantaged children, requiring commitment, empathy, and vigilance to ensure a fun and safe learning environment.

2020 - 21 Environmental Consultant Intern, Ensight

• Assisted consultancy projects delivering supply chain carbon footprint analysis.

OTHER SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Full UK driver's license, NVLBQ qualified life saver, Surfing, Tennis, Olympic Weightlifting, Guitar, Piano